# Joshua Everett

Website: joshuaeverett.co.uk Email: joshuaeverett95@gmail.com Mobile: +44 (0)7758 664365

I'm a Senior Software Engineer, with 5 years' experience in Android app development. I've used this experience to develop the design system for Deliveroo's Android apps, and building new features/providing maintenance on the BBC Sport/iPlayer apps, ensuring quality and delivering value.

I work to agile practices and am completely involved throughout the entire development process alongside an interdisciplinary team of developers, UX, test and product.

I'm an accessibility champion, advocating on how to meet accessibility requirements building consideration into a team's processes.

# **Employment**

Senior Design System Engineer - Deliveroo, Remote

08/2022 - Present

Senior Android developer in the team owning Deliveroo's design system. Responsible for the implementation and maintenance of the design system foundations and components across all four Android apps.

### Work delivered:

- Android library for design tokens, built with Style Dictionary for views and Jetpack Compose.
- Improved tooling for design system components, adding theme configuration to browser app.
- Introduce themed icon to the Deliveroo app, utilising modern Android OS features.

Senior Software Engineer - BBC iPlayer, Manchester

07/2021 - 07/2022

Senior developer on the BBC iPlayer Android app, with ~7 million users. Responsible for the video player, maintaining the legacy code as well as development of new features in Kotlin. Lead app releases through Google Play and Amazon Consoles. Mentoring of new developers joining the team, as well as junior developers across the BBC.

### Work delivered:

- Development of heavily requested autoplay to next episode feature, utilising a feature toggle.
- Improved monitoring for issue diagnosis, collaborating with the media player team.
- Enabling Jetpack Compose to be used in the app, setting up theming and a sample app.

Software Engineer - BBC Sport, Manchester

08/2019 - 07/2021

Developing the BBC Sport app with ~2 million users. Heavily involved in collaboration with the News team to develop a shared component library, providing reusable UI to both apps. Set up a cross department working group for Accessibility, improving processes and visibility of legacy issues.

#### Work delivered:

- New version of article pages built with shared component library, loading ~6x faster.
- Creation of a new onboarding experience, prioritising accessibility and screen reader users.
- Running multivariate experiments with users, informing the approach to mandatory sign-in.

```
Graduate Software Engineer - BBC, London/Manchester 09/2017 - 08/2019
```

Completed 6-month rotations for iPlayer TV, journalism tools and Sport Android app teams. Gained a wide range of experience by working with different teams/types of agile development. Volunteered at STEM sessions running coding challenges with school children, as well as at BBC events.

```
Web Developer - Intergral GmbH, Stuttgart
```

06/2015 - 08/2016

Worked within the web team developing a cloud service for the core product, FusionReactor. Gaining experience on web frameworks, understanding and delivering requirements into the product. Mentored and paired with other developers, running onboarding for the next placement.

### Skills

### Android Development

Building Android apps using Kotlin and Java in Android Studio. Strong knowledge in concepts such as layouts, theming, coroutines and architecture patterns (MVVM, MVC). Experience using testing frameworks (JUnit, Espresso). Usage of modern Android tools such as Jetpack libraries including Jetpack Compose. Building and publishing Android libraries.

# {} Software Development

Working within an agile team, collaborating with other developers through pairing on tasks and code reviews. Adhering to good software engineering principles such as SOLID, ensuring I write easy to understand and maintainable code. Extensive experience using Git with Github.

#### Accessibility

Extensive knowledge in making Android apps accessible following WCAG/BBC guidelines, using TalkBack and testing with Android's Accessibility Suite. Recognition of different disabilities, the additional needs associated, and the assistive technology required.

# P.

## Design Systems/User Experience

Contributed to the design system bringing in technical considerations. Ran research sessions with users gaining insight into how they use app functionality. Working alongside UX to develop accessible designs/interactions. Proficient with Material Design concepts.



### Cloud Development

Experience with AWS, using services like CloudWatch to gather and query monitoring events. Use of CI tools such as Github Actions, Bitrise, CircleCI and Jenkins to ensure continuous delivery. Running emulator and device tests on Firebase, utilising Fladle.

#### **</>** Web Development

Ability to develop and host modern web applications from scratch, using libraries such as React. Build services on AWS with TypeScript. Strong knowledge with CSS. Usage of hybrid mobile frameworks such as ionic/react native.

# Education

# Loughborough University - Info Management & Web Development 2013 - 2017

Classification: First class BSc (hons) with year in industry.

**Key Modules**: Final year project (building a hybrid app on Android and iOS for attending concerts), mobile app development, advanced web development, UX design, Human-Computer Interaction. Awards: Awarded two team project prizes, presented for achieving the highest mark in each coursework deliverable.

Hinchingbrooke School - Secondary School and Sixth Form 2006 - 2013

**A-Levels**: Maths (A), IT (B), Geography (C) - **GCSE**: 2 A\*s, A, 7 Bs, C (including A\* in Maths and IT)

### Interests

Music: Passion for live music and collecting vinyl records, as well as playing guitar and bass. **Sport**: I love playing football, keeping active, and following formula 1, football, cricket and the NFL. **Creativity**: I've recently got into photography and love creative projects like drawing and painting.

References can be provided upon request. For more information on me and my work/projects please visit my website.